<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Integrations IT Solutions</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Integrations IT Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Official Curriculum &amp; ESI Classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/microsoft-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/microsoft-classes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Please find below a comprehensive list of official Microsoft classes that I currently teach, including those related to Copilots, AI, and Microsoft 365. These classes are designed to enhance your skills in developing low-code and pro-code agents and copilots for Microsoft 365, as well as other related technologies. MOC&amp;rsquo;s are only available through Microsoft Learning Partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general--agentic-ai&#34;&gt;General &amp;amp; Agentic AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-102 Designing and implementing a Microsoft Azure Al Solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3002 Create document intelligence solutions with Azure Al Document Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3003 Build a natural language processing solution with Azure Al Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3004 Build an Azure Al Vision solution with Azure Al services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3016 Develop custom copilots with Azure Al Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3017 Microsoft Al for business leaders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3018 Copilot Foundations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3019 Build Al Apps with Azure Database for PostgreSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al-3022 Implement Al Skills in Azure Al Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI-3026 Develop AI Agents on Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;copilot--modern-workplace-microsoft-365&#34;&gt;Copilot &amp;amp; Modern Workplace Microsoft 365&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4004 Empower your workforce with Microsoft 365 Copilot Use Cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4005 Craft effective prompts for Microsoft 365 Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4008 Microsoft 365 Copilot Interactive Experience for Executives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4009 Extend Microsoft Copilot for Microsoft 365 with Copilot Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4010 Extend Microsoft 365 Copilot with declarative agents by using Visual Studio Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4012 Microsoft Copilot Interactive Experience for Executives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4014 Build a foundation to extend Microsoft 365 Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4015 Build custom agents for Microsoft Teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4017 Manage and extend Microsoft 365 Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4018: Draft, analyze, and present with Microsoft 365 Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MS-4019: Transform your everyday business processes with agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PL-7008 Create agents in Microsoft Copilot Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;azure-ai-driven-software-engineering-devops--automation&#34;&gt;Azure AI-Driven Software Engineering, DevOps &amp;amp; Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-2003 Deploy cloud-native apps using Azure Container Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-2008 DevOps foundations: The core principles and practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-2007: Accelerate app development by using GitHub Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-2009 Build distributed apps with .NET Aspire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-204 Develop Solutions for Microsoft Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AZ-400 Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GH-200 Automate your workflow with GitHub Actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GH-300 GitHub Copilot Fundamentals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data--databases&#34;&gt;Data &amp;amp; Databases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DP-3015 Getting Started with Cosmos DB NoSQL Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DP-3021 Configure and migrate to Azure Database for PostgreSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DP-420 Designing and Implementing Cloud-Native Applications Using Microsoft Azure Cosmos DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enterprise-skill-initiative---esi&#34;&gt;Enterprise Skill Initiative - ESI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DW-100 Copilot Business Value Bootcamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DW-102 Building and extending AI-Powered Copilots with Copilot Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DW-103 Securing and Governing Copilot for Microsoft 365 with Microsoft Purview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DW-200 Azure OpenAI Workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DW-201: Building and modernizing AI Apps on Azure Workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Agents and Copilots using Semantic Kernel and Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/agents-copilots-sk-agent-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/agents-copilots-sk-agent-service/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This in-depth course that takes developers from foundational concepts to advanced multi-agent orchestration using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s AI ecosystem. The course begins with Azure AI Foundry essentials, covering hubs, projects, and resources while establishing expertise in prompt engineering, GitHub Models, and the Agent-to-Agent (A2A) protocol fundamentals. Students dive deep into Semantic Kernel development, mastering chat completion, multi-modal capabilities, and advanced prompt templating using YAML, Handlebar, and Liquid formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum provides extensive coverage of Semantic Kernel&amp;rsquo;s plugin architecture, including native functions, OpenAPI integrations, and MCP server implementations, alongside Kernel Memory and vector store connectors for RAG solutions. Participants will master both the Semantic Kernel Agent and Process Frameworks, learning to build multi-step task agents with personas while choosing between Orleans and Dapr runtimes. The course emphasizes Azure AI Foundry&amp;rsquo;s multi-agent solutions, teaching students to leverage the Azure AI Agent Service with action tools (code interpreters, function calling) and knowledge tools (file search, Azure AI Search, Bing Grounding).&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Applications using GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/vibe-coding-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/vibe-coding-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This comprehensive one-day online class, &amp;ldquo;Developing Applications using GitHub Copilot,&amp;rdquo; is designed to help developers maximize productivity and code quality by fully leveraging GitHub Copilot&amp;rsquo;s AI-assisted development features. The course focuses on practical usage: Configuring Copilot, prompt engineering, and selecting the right model for your needs. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to generate and edit code efficiently, use context and chat features, and streamline multi-file development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will discover how to use Copilot for refactoring, error fixing, and automating repetitive tasks, as well as integrating Copilot into source control workflows for better collaboration. The course also covers generating high-quality documentation, including code comments and architecture diagrams with Mermaid.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Low- and Pro-Code Agents and Copilots for Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/develop-copilots-m365/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/develop-copilots-m365/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Join our comprehensive course designed for Microsoft 365 and AI developers, as well as decision-makers, to master the art of developing low-code and pro-code agents and copilots for Microsoft 365. This program promises to elevate your development skills, making you proficient in the latest tools and techniques to enhance productivity within the Microsoft 365 ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this journey, you will first embark on an exploration into the world of Microsoft 365 and its Copilot ecosystem. You will uncover the unique value of connectors versus plugins and delve into the many extensibility options available. As you progress, you will learn to build plugins and connectors for Microsoft Copilot using the Teams Toolkit, gaining insights into architectural extensions and how to integrate enterprise data with Microsoft Graph Connectors, thus adding specialized skills through plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing &amp; Implementing Cloud Native Applications using Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/cloud-native-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/cloud-native-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This five days comprehensive workshop guides you through the journey of designing and implementing cloud-native applications using Microsoft Azure&amp;rsquo;s powerful ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to evolve from monolithic architectures to scalable microservices, master containerization with Azure Container Apps, leverage .NET Aspire and Dapr for distributed application development, implement event-driven architectures, and optimize application performance and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll gain hands-on experience with modern cloud patterns, Azure services integration, and best practices for building resilient, scalable applications in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Angular Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/angular-advanced-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/angular-advanced-development/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This advanced Angular five days workshop is designed for experienced developers aiming to master modern Angular techniques and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covering topics from standalone components, reactive programming with RxJS and Signals, to state management with NgRx, advanced routing, and comprehensive testing strategies, the course offers a deep dive into the Angular ecosystem. Participants will also explore reusability with libraries and Nx, real-time micro-frontends, progressive web apps, and performance optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through hands-on modules, attendees will gain practical skills to architect, test, and optimize complex Angular applications.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Development Essentials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/angular-development-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/angular-development-essentials/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This five days workshop provides a comprehensive introduction to modern Angular development, covering essential concepts such as Angular related TypeScript fundamentals, dependency injection, and component architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will learn best practices for building responsive user interfaces, managing state, and implementing reactive programming with Signals and RxJS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum also includes hands-on guidance for testing, securing, and publishing Angular applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end, attendees will be equipped to develop robust, maintainable, and scalable Angular projects using current industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Development Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/m356-development-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/m356-development-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The five days workshop Microsoft 365 Development Fundamentals is a series of modules that provide an in-depth introduction to Microsoft 365 development. It covers theory, demos, hands-on labs as well as deployment and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop is designed for developers aiming to implement Microsoft 365 solutions and covers the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Microsoft 365 Development: Provides an overview of Microsoft 365 services, apps, and extension patterns, and discusses the integration with Azure and app deployment processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
