<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft 365 on Integrations IT Solutions</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/microsoft-365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft 365 on Integrations IT Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/microsoft-365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Develop Low- and Pro-Code Agents and Copilots for Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/develop-copilots-m365/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/develop-copilots-m365/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Join our comprehensive course designed for Microsoft 365 and AI developers, as well as decision-makers, to master the art of developing low-code and pro-code agents and copilots for Microsoft 365. This program promises to elevate your development skills, making you proficient in the latest tools and techniques to enhance productivity within the Microsoft 365 ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this journey, you will first embark on an exploration into the world of Microsoft 365 and its Copilot ecosystem. You will uncover the unique value of connectors versus plugins and delve into the many extensibility options available. As you progress, you will learn to build plugins and connectors for Microsoft Copilot using the Teams Toolkit, gaining insights into architectural extensions and how to integrate enterprise data with Microsoft Graph Connectors, thus adding specialized skills through plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Development Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/m356-development-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/m356-development-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The five days workshop Microsoft 365 Development Fundamentals is a series of modules that provide an in-depth introduction to Microsoft 365 development. It covers theory, demos, hands-on labs as well as deployment and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop is designed for developers aiming to implement Microsoft 365 solutions and covers the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Microsoft 365 Development: Provides an overview of Microsoft 365 services, apps, and extension patterns, and discusses the integration with Azure and app deployment processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
